[{"id": "5ff14015b0ee8c595b6d3994", "question": "In what city was the Diary of Anne Frank written?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590720d03745b36be73039f3", "question": "What year did Disney release a 3D motion-capture adaptation of \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78d", "question": "Cha dao is the art of what?", "answer": "Making tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede45f6ce05a3942286ddd", "question": "Who penned the classic songs \"Bad Moon Rising\", \"Who'll Stop The Rain\", and \"Lodi\"?", "answer": "John Fogarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e93", "question": "What movie did the villain Verbal Kint appear in?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c112", "question": "What country was figure skater Elvis Stojko born in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911d", "question": "What year did E. M. Forster publish the novel \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "1910", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b604", "question": "What war do the girls in \"Little Women\" grow up during?", "answer": "The Civil War", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25916b63e5727cf5a484b", "question": "What year did The Outhere Brothers release the song \"Boom Boom Boom\"?", "answer": "1995", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b549", "question": "What is \"hotel-Dieu\" in France?", "answer": "A hospital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989a", "question": "What dancer from Omaha was born Fred Austerlitz?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdd", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured David Bowie and Rip Torn?", "answer": "The Man Who Fell to Earth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c593", "question": "What\u2019s a tropical cyclone called when its winds reach 74 miles per hour?", "answer": "A Hurricane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fc", "question": "Who played Lester Burnham in \"American Beauty\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdaffe65ff7d326b622a5e", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e9", "question": "How many calories do the US Postal Service stamps contain?", "answer": "One-tenth of a calorie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa55", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c66", "question": "What comic strip cat was created by Otto Messmer and Pat Sullivan in 1919?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a40fcf93664eb10486c1", "question": "Despite being referred to as Francine throughout the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic book series, what is this character\u2019s real first name?", "answer": "Helen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b2", "question": "What is Agnes Skinner's nickname for Seymour in The Simpsons TV show?", "answer": "Spanky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b0", "question": "If you were infected with the variola virus, what disease did you have?", "answer": "Smallpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c313", "question": "How many times a year does the sun rise and set at the North Pole?", "answer": "Once", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d69", "question": "Who played the role of TV's B. J. Poteet?", "answer": "Judith Ivey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbe7d003d27d341092bcf", "question": "Which South American city is laid out in the shape of a puma?", "answer": "Cusco, Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8e", "question": "What was the name of Paul McCartney's backup group from 1971 to 1981?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fd", "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?", "answer": "The big one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54a", "question": "The mouth of what bay is located between Cape Charles and Cape Henry?", "answer": "Chesapeake Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb6", "question": "Who was married to Princess Anne in 1992?", "answer": "Tim Lawrence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed6", "question": "Who fights crime alongside a German shepherd named Ace?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f0", "question": "What name was adopted by boxing champion Cassius Marcellus Clay Jr.?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb085fbcf631c2414a13b50", "question": "Who sings the \"Friends\" theme song?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d263745b36be73039d4", "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?", "answer": "Operation Osoaviakhim", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c4", "question": "When did Indira Gandhi's first term as Prime Minister of India begin?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a397", "question": "What is \"The Windy City\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f72bba9e54d890926f6ed", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1be6baab681b0929219c", "question": "What year did Porsche introduce the 911?", "answer": "1963", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff259af31a458464a93c46e", "question": "If a person's candle flame goes off on the night of Halloween, it indicates that the person is with what?", "answer": "A ghost", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931a", "question": "In the 1967 movie \"Cool Hand Luke\", how many hard-boiled eggs does Lucas eat in one hour?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b2a4e662d71a53650fdb", "question": "What are the first names of Lord Voldemort's parents?", "answer": "Tom and Merope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ff43fe83fe1f2a824c4c", "question": "Why did US President Theodore Roosevelt ban Christmas trees in the White House in 1901?", "answer": "He banned the trees during his first year in office due to him being \"a devoted environmentalist\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e93f47ccba3ffe45786cc", "question": "What year was Buddy Holly born?", "answer": "1936", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a8", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb13865ff7d326b622a68", "question": "What is the atomic number of Curium?", "answer": "96", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ec9d08d98002fdd633bd", "question": "Equatorial Guinea gained independence from which country in 1968?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf55", "question": "This drink is made from espresso coffee, hot milk and chocolate?", "answer": "Mocha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968e", "question": "Who received an Oscar for directing the 1986 movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Oliver Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c233", "question": "What fashion designer was responsible for the \"New Look\"?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f70d7a9e54d890926f6d8", "question": "How many states does Yellowstone National Park cover?", "answer": "Three -- Wyoming is home to 96% of the park, including the famed Old Faithful geyser, but 1% is in Idaho, and 3% is in Montana.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb09df83302ff91e4649e", "question": "Who directed the 1972 film \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a1", "question": "Which company was founded first - Apple or Microsoft?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df7", "question": "What is the subject of Claude Lanzmann's award-winning nine-hour film \"Shoah\"?", "answer": "The Holocaust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3236bdbf195a31e15d73be", "question": "\"Oliver's Story\" was the sequel to which best-seller by Erich Segal?", "answer": "Love Story", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339524", "question": "What movie character said the line \"Go ahead, make my day\"?", "answer": "Harry Callahan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af44", "question": "What war ended at the Battle of San Jacinto?", "answer": "Texas Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ced9877e98cb97778a47", "question": "What state is home to the Crazy Horse Memorial?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba92", "question": "What puzzle toy, invented in Hungary, was the best-\u00adselling toy of 1981?", "answer": "Rubik\u2019s Cube", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff1407db0ee8c595b6d399d", "question": "Which Italian town is the setting for Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet?", "answer": "Verona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b91", "question": "What daily comic strip features occasional visits from Bob the Dinosaur, \"king of the wedgies\"?", "answer": "Dilbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde5129c6c6b019850c9a8d", "question": "Who was the first King of the Northern Ten Tribes of Israel during the time of the Divided Kingdom?", "answer": "Jeroboam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f02bff048f679a45aa98", "question": "Philophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Love", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1f", "question": "Which body part was Achilles weak spot?", "answer": "His heel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c604", "question": "Which planet is named after the God of Love?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f5", "question": "What gender are clownfish?", "answer": "They are hermaphrodites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3d5444f0f6af5b066639", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Don't Pay The Ferryman\"?", "answer": "Chris de Burgh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c189", "question": "Who was born Mark Feld?", "answer": "Marc Bolan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339342", "question": "Who is Stan's sister on the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Shelley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a911", "question": "What major river runs through Buenos Aires?", "answer": "Rio de la Plata", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b69910ae762b54eb9be9416", "question": "Up until the modern times, what type of gift was usually associated with 20th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b328", "question": "What state did Harry Truman represent as a US Senator before becoming President of the Unites States?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5750c73aa70ea0b70b35", "question": "Which state features the one-word motto \"Excelsior\u201d?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f167c0f7c52aae91cc07bd", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau has a coast on which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fed2be1ec223966ae8f8914", "question": "Who wrote The Monkees' #1 hit \"I'm a Believer\"?", "answer": "Neil Diamond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef62f16ce05a3942286e61", "question": "What was the first song featuring rap to top the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "\"Rapture\" by Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339301", "question": "In the movie \"Leon\", who plays the role of Mathilda?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae64", "question": "On July 4, 1776, how many English colonies proclaimed a Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "13", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30f", "question": "Who sang the 1979 song \"Family Tradition\"?", "answer": "Hank Williams Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a79620565ad31a57c7eb", "question": "Which state's flag was designed by a 7th grader?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe527851bf59ab7d2e380fa", "question": "How tall are the Hollywood sign letters?", "answer": "45 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339371", "question": "What nationality does Teddy claim to be in the movie \"Stand By Me\"?", "answer": "French", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a797", "question": "Havana is located on which side of Cuba?", "answer": "The west", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae96", "question": "The 16th Constitutional Amendment, enacted in 1913 allowed the US federal government to do what?", "answer": "Tax personal income", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb3", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Anatevka\"?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ea", "question": "What singer began his career fronting the bands of Harry James and Tommy Dorsey in the 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35b", "question": "What is a \"kartoffel\" in Hamburg?", "answer": "A potato", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e0", "question": "What name is given to the speed at which airplanes produce a sonic boom?", "answer": "Mach 1", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c627", "question": "In Astronomy, what does the \"Seven Sisters\" refer to?", "answer": "The Pleiades", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5fc", "question": "What river begins at Lake Itasca?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e1", "question": "What is the last name of the brothers in the band AC/DC?", "answer": "Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb35ac72627b8fe95581be9", "question": "In what country was Mel Gibson born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd4", "question": "Who is often credited with breaking hip hop into mainstream music?", "answer": "Run D.M.C.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c920", "question": "The Amazon river dolphins are what colour?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a613", "question": "Name the largest landlocked country in Europe?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937e9c308d98002fdd6339d", "question": "Which side of the brain is responsible for logic and rational thought?", "answer": "The left side", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa5658c73aa70ea0b70b2a", "question": "What color do people wear for the New Year in Brazil?", "answer": "White", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071e773745b36be73039e3", "question": "What year saw the release of issue #1 of the \"Revival\" comic book series?", "answer": "2012", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb2", "question": "Golda Meir was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7b", "question": "Who was the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b3", "question": "What is a parsec a unit of?", "answer": "Length", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d2", "question": "Who played the role of C.K. Dexter-Haven in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c8", "question": "\"To swoon\" is to what?", "answer": "Faint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a806", "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9d", "question": "What is the profession of Jon Cryer's character on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Chiropractor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8feee01dd7bf43be5e85e", "question": "Whose image is on the U.S. half-dollar from 1916 to 1947?", "answer": "Lady Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a304", "question": "What was singer George Jones' animal nickname?", "answer": "The Possum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb08", "question": "Which planet is orbited by the moon Charon?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d1", "question": "For what movie did Jack Nicholson win his first Academy Award?", "answer": "One Flew Over The Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339993", "question": "What are the names of Rachael's two sisters on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Amy and Jill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of harvest and agriculture?", "answer": "Demeter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970d", "question": "Actor Jason Lee was a professional in which sport?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590723043745b36be7303a04", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Richard Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacc", "question": "Who perfected the first American revolver?", "answer": "Samuel Colt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16a27f7c52aae91cc07d8", "question": "Who is the son of Sycorax in Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Caliban", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b8", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Who Made Who\"?", "answer": "AC/DC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973c", "question": "Who won an Oscar for the theme song from the movie \"Shaft\"?", "answer": "Isaac Hayes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5b", "question": "In 1995, Heather Whitestone became the first Miss America to have what disability?", "answer": "She was deaf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf6", "question": "Which British physician developed the first effective vaccine against smallpox?", "answer": "Edward Jenner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9319574a5ce6b56b8235", "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of youth?", "answer": "Hebe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338deb", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"cookie\"?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa551cc73aa70ea0b70b21", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c7", "question": "Who is the subject of Jean Anouilh's play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896a", "question": "Which James Bond novel is told in the first person by a fictional character called Vivienne Michel?", "answer": "The Spy Who Loved Me", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf7bcdb37b32637bdc44c7", "question": "What part of the atom has no charge?", "answer": "Neutron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec881aec223966ae8f881b", "question": "Blondie of the film \"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "\"the Man with No Name\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe655daae7e414034b5aebc", "question": "Where did Athena first emerge?", "answer": "From the head of Zeus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7a", "question": "What company was founded in 1976 by \"the two Steves\"?", "answer": "Apple Computer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927d", "question": "In season 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" what is the name of the alliance that included Dominic, Cassie, Keith and Lawon?", "answer": "The Regulators", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e8cdfe83fe1f2a824bdf", "question": "Which rebellious leader of the Catuvellauni tribe was caught and taken to Rome in AD 50, then pardoned by Emperor Claudius?", "answer": "Caractacus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04f", "question": "What was the only James Bond film to crack the top-ten list for highest grossing movies of the 1960s?", "answer": "Thunderball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358c035db0d66a186cb55a", "question": "The \"Arenga Micrantha\" species of flowering plants is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "The Tibetan sugar palm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b7cfe662d71a53651018", "question": "In which city is the Prado Art Gallery?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81bfed0de9af39e9d467e", "question": "The term \"ok\" caught on during what president's campaign?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cb70db4f96e155acab35d34", "question": "What is the national animal of Scotland?", "answer": "Unicorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e94527ccba3ffe45786d2", "question": "What year was the element Californium first synthesized?", "answer": "1950", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c4", "question": "Who played the role of Jenna Maroney on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Jane Krakowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b573", "question": "What sport is Jenson Button associated with?", "answer": "Motorsport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e97cfebfabb9c85d8a966", "question": "What TV show has the character Michael Stivic?", "answer": "All in the Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6f", "question": "What are described by the terms rep, challis and foulard?", "answer": "Neckties", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c15", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the fifth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Diseased livestock", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c60", "question": "George Lucas' first full feature film, \"THX 1138\" was released in what year?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16b", "question": "What year was the film \"The Day of the Jackal\" released?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f166daf7c52aae91cc07b3", "question": "Which drug, later found to have devastating side effects, was launched in 1957 to help pregnant women overcome morning sickness?", "answer": "Thalidomide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b4afe662d71a53650fee", "question": "What Edgar Allan Poe work launched his writing career?", "answer": "\"The Raven\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3780a0ada16518afdc04f", "question": "What part of a chocolate bunny should be eaten first according to a majority of Americans?", "answer": "Ears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b851", "question": "In chess, which piece only moves diagonally?", "answer": "The bishop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08d", "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Ellen Degeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fce4a4edfd43a087adc4", "question": "What number is represented by \"X\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "10", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d076e3870e6f05ba60085f", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the shrew's last name?", "answer": "Minola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c550fbde8045e48466ab", "question": "Which ocean mammal is nicknamed the killer whale?", "answer": "Orca -- Orcas are called killer whales due to their aggression while hunting prey.  However, orcas are large dolphins, not whales.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5921fc49a4edfd43a087adbf", "question": "What French word describes the person working at the front desk of a hotel?", "answer": "Concierge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af95", "question": "In what year did the Spanish Civil War begin?", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901dc4b709c1c34536e6eb5", "question": "What does someone become after being canonized?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017385344491cbd7c5a1798", "question": "During what years were Thomas Jefferson nickels made with siver?", "answer": "1942 to 1945 -- Due to a wartime shortage of nickel metal, nickel coins were minted using 35% silver, 56% copper and 9% manganese.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a82c9d816e292245c19", "question": "What artist created a 43 ft sculpture of a West Highland White Terrier puppy?", "answer": "Jeff Koons (He was commissioned to create the piece for Arolsen Castle in Germany.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d968908b8581f80b092a7", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73a", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sunflower State\"?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2e", "question": "What valley holds the record for the highest temperature recorded on American soil?", "answer": "Death Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b438", "question": "Which historical figure passed away on April 18, 1955?", "answer": "Albert Einstein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d09", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Sodoff Baldrick?", "answer": "Edmund Blackadder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ff", "question": "What is the name of the Austrian Monk who formulated the basic laws of genetics?", "answer": "Gregor Mendel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c599", "question": "What fungus is used in making bread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea412bff048f679a45ab6d", "question": "What physical constant did Henry Cavendish first determine using two weights and a cantilever?", "answer": "Gravitational Constant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa4a", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde7", "question": "What sport has thirteen players per team in \"league\" rules but fifteen in \"union\" play?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938c", "question": "What is Doc allergic to in the movie \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "Synthetics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338919", "question": "Who runs the orphanage in the musical \"Annie\"?", "answer": "Miss Hannigan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39d", "question": "What did James Ritty invent in 1879?", "answer": "Cash register", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b887", "question": "What does the abbreviation YMCA stand for?", "answer": "Young Men's Christian Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3ae6ce05a3942286f26", "question": "John Paul Jones was the bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad76", "question": "Whose tomb was found in the Valley of the Kings in Egypt?", "answer": "Tutankhamun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b7", "question": "When did boxer John L. Sullivan die?", "answer": "1918", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfdb79616e6c6d4eba4f8", "question": "On the hit show \"Seinfeld\" what was Kramer's first name? ", "answer": "Cosmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636c6c967692ea851899ab", "question": "What popular destination helped popularize hot dogs in the US in the 19th century?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94827ccba3ffe45786d4", "question": "What year was the Battle of Bannockburn?", "answer": "1314", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071d823745b36be73039d9", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339632", "question": "In the 1995 movie \"Babe\", what Christmas carol does Babe sing?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb5057e83c707845b211e", "question": "What is Mars' atmosphere mostly made of?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ac", "question": "What city is often mistakenly referred to as the \"Lost City of the Incas\"?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe6", "question": "Who got its name by combining the Japanese words for \"gorilla\" and \"whale\"?", "answer": "Godzilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6ec7e83c707845b216f", "question": "Tommy Williams was caught stealing what from a shop in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ec", "question": "What color is a Livestrong bracelet?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b222", "question": "What city was William McKinley killed in?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96fae23c87fd04dd15e44", "question": "Which Christmas song was actually written for Thanksgiving?", "answer": "\"Jingle Bells\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7690ceec85e375820b2ab", "question": "What structure links Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Ambassador Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339867", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what is it that Dumbo is made fun of for?", "answer": "His large ears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aef", "question": "What sitcom character was constantly called \"Butthead\" by his bratty big brother Wayne?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ca", "question": "Who sang the 1956 song \"Ape Call\"?", "answer": "Nervous Norvus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac8", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25ef876682715b82711cd7", "question": "\"Photo Journal\" was a weekly newspaper written and sold in which country until 1981?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba44", "question": "The philanthropist, Andrew Carnegie, made his fortune in what industry?", "answer": "Steel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa9126ce05a3942286edb", "question": "What classic novel did TV's \"Big Brother\" get its name from?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728cb56bcd28c11938328a", "question": "What is the capital of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c881fbde8045e48466da", "question": "Vermillion is a shade of which color?", "answer": "Vermillion is a brilliant red pigment made from mercury sulfide.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24c", "question": "What year was Bryan Adams' \"Cuts Like a Knife\" album released in?", "answer": "1983", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d8", "question": "Who was said to float like a butterfly and sting like a bee?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe64146ae7e414034b5aeaa", "question": "Approximately how long did the gunfight at the O.K Corral in Tombstone, Arizona last?", "answer": "Thirty seconds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf11", "question": "Who was the first professional footballer to be knighted?", "answer": "Sir Stanley Matthews\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd3a5ec223966ae8f88c6", "question": "What famous film character says: \"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse\"?", "answer": "Vito Corleone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec5", "question": "Which Saint was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral in 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe2", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14a", "question": "What was Walt Disney's middle name?", "answer": "Elias", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba95a7e83c707845b20d5", "question": "Which astronomical celestial event generally occurs on the same date as the International Day of Happiness?", "answer": "March Equinox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a570", "question": "What US city is famous for its French Quarter?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e3d4fe83fe1f2a824bab", "question": "What was the significance of Mt. Suribachi?", "answer": "It was the site of a major battle on Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae72", "question": "What berries did pregnant women of the Middle Ages avoid for fear their children would be born with birthmarks?", "answer": "Strawberries", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5afad7f8430e050a5df0d111", "question": "What is emitted from a nuclear reaction that can cause another fission?", "answer": "A Neutron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a79a", "question": "What is the capital of Canada?", "answer": "Ottawa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe523921bf59ab7d2e380f0", "question": "In which country would you find fried meatballs served with potatoes and gravy called frikadeller?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c651", "question": "How many daily tides are there?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f0d6ff048f679a45aaa8", "question": "Trypanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Needles or injections", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7667deec85e375820b281", "question": "In what country would you celebrate \"Carnival\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c69", "question": "What literary character, in a novel by Cervantes, had a sidekick named Sancho Panza?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339550", "question": "Who was Gordon Shumway?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65984ae7e414034b5af01", "question": "Which Founding Father had a house which was discovered to have had about 1200 bone pieces from about ten human skeletons?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14380b0ee8c595b6d39b2", "question": "Who wrote the 15th century novel \"The Tale of Two Lovers\"?", "answer": "Pope Pius II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a782", "question": "What line of Latitude lies at 23 degrees and 27 minutes north of the equator?", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e3ccfe83fe1f2a824baa", "question": "What statement best characterizes the series of battles in the Pacific following the Battle of Guadalcanal?", "answer": "With each battle, the Japanese soldiers increasingly fought to the death", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09b", "question": "What was the first Mickey Mouse cartoon?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff1", "question": "Who wrote the \"Noddy\" books?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029dd3cad1ec93f27df752", "question": "How is a Long black coffee different from an Americano?", "answer": "The espresso is poured on top of the hot water, instead of before", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c700", "question": "On the periodic table, an element\u2019s atomic number represents the number of what in it's atom?", "answer": "Protons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1158c4fea7fe947a22267", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b718", "question": "Citizens of what empire are credited with starting the tradition of gift giving?", "answer": "Romans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338948", "question": "Which author hosted a 1960 fishing competition that Fidel Castro won?", "answer": "Ernest Hemmingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999c", "question": "What 60\u2019s TV series featured the three Bradley daughters, Betty Jo, Billie Jo, and Bobbie Jo?", "answer": "Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b1", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adec", "question": "What year was the computer mouse first patented?", "answer": "1970", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b225", "question": "In which city was American actor Bob Crane murdered?", "answer": "Scottsdale, Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69b3920565ad31a57c75d", "question": "What was the largest battleship in World War II?", "answer": "Yamato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c0", "question": "What is the name of Frodo's faithful gardener in \"The Lord of the Rings\"?", "answer": "Sam Gamgee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c89d23011619dd6d415483", "question": "What disappeared from the town of South Park, forcing Randy to relocate his family to a refugee camp in California?", "answer": "The Internet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba4d8874c93a3298b2149", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Mount Snowdon?", "answer": "Yr Wyddfa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e45", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a078", "question": "Five out of six of the Village People have got what?", "answer": "Moustaches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c83", "question": "What forest was home to Robin Hood and his band of Merry Men?", "answer": "Sherwood Forest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6012187f63c99d48cd169af3", "question": "What was Hugh Hefner\u2019s jet plane named?", "answer": "Big bunny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cdcd7bd84c0ea43ad42f", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which Eastern European country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64a", "question": "What type of clam chowder is made with a tomato-based sauce?", "answer": "Manhattan clam chowder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20eab31a458464a93c428", "question": "Who composed \"Ride of the Valkyries\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f122ff048f679a45aaae", "question": "Zoophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "science"}]